Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of Caricatures and Cartoons 1643, 1756-1943, 1977 PR 10
New-York Historical Society
- Series V. Civil War and Post-War Period, 1860-1868
  - Above: Duncan's Illustrated Edition of Popes Essays. Vol. 2. Below: Genl. Pope complacently views Jeb Stewart plundering his quarters and taking all his clean clothes and important papers. The "backs of the enemy" considered very disgusting. [General John Pope], 1862 (Folder FF-81, Item 1862-2)
    Lithograph: Lith. of B. Duncan, Columbia, SC. Acquisition(?) date on front: Apr. 16, 1906.
  - Above: Duncan's Illustrated Edition of Popes Essays. Vol. 3. Below: [sheet torn] quences of that arch rebel Jeff Davis retaliatory order, as witnessed on Manassas plains Aug. 30 [sheet torn] second season of Bull Run races. Privates distanced by the Officers. [General John Pope], 1862 (Folder FF-81, Item 1862-3)
  - Above: Duncan's Illustrated Edition of Popes Essays. Vol. 4. Below: The hero who has preserved the Union by subjugating the South, undertakes another 'small job' of putting down the north western Indians. [General John Pope], 1862 (Folder FF-81, Item 1862-4)
  - Above: Dissolving Views of Richmond. Scene 1st. Below: The Youthful Napoleon quietly sitteth down 'upon his base' before Richmond intending to take it when he gets ready. [General McClellan], 1862 (Folder FF-81, Item 1862-5)
  - Above: Dissolving Views of Richmond. Scene 2nd. Below: He concludeth to change ye base of his operations, and is ably seconded therein by ye gallant Stonewall. He giveth way to pressure coming from the rear. [General McClellan], 1862 (Folder FF-81, Item 1862-6)
  - Above: Dissolving Views of Richmond. Scene 3rd. Below: He maketh an important "strategic movement" and again findeth his friend "Stonewall" at hand ready to assist him. [General McClellan], 1862 (Folder FF-81, Item 1862-7)
  - Above: Dissolving Views of Richmond. Section 4th. Below: The "small" Napoleon after the fatigues of the week, congratulates his victorious companions on the 4th of July for their gallant deeds. [General McClellan], 1862 (Folder FF-81, Item 1862-8)
    Lithograph: B. Duncan, Columbia, SC. Acquisition(?) date on front: Apr. 16/06.
  - Terrible Effects of my First Bombshells in Boston. An Illustration to Train's Memorable Speech Delivered in the Music Hall, Boston, Septr. 25, 1862. [George F. Train] (Folder FF-81, Item 1862-9)
    Acquisition(?) date on front: Apr. 16, 1906.
  - Oakley Hall and the Chamber of Commerce. [Mayor Opdyke Oakley Hall], 1862 (Folder FF-81, Item 1862-10)
    Wood engraving: Signed Fits. Acquisition(?) date on front: Sept. 17, 1897.
  - The Old General Ready for a "Movement". [Winfield Scott], 1862 (Folder FF-81, Item 1862-11)
  - Shadows of the Times. Pl. 1-3. [In Silhouette] [Civil War], 1862 (Folder FF-81, Item 1862-12 (Plates 1,2,3))
    Lithographs: P. Kramer, del. Entered ... 1862 by P. Kramer & C. Muringer, Phila. Acquisition(?) date on front: Apr. 16, 1906.
  - The Future of the Great Republic, As Depicted by a Correspondent of the New York Times. [Satirical comparisons of the Union and French military], 1862 (Folder FF-81, Item 1862-13)
    From an illustrated newspaper of Nov. 15, 1862.
  - The Christmas Tree of the Federal Army. [Secession traitors hanging as ornaments], 1862 (Folder FF-81, Item 1862-14)
    From an illustrated newspaper of Jan 4, 1862.
  - [No Title] Drawing shows a man (Uncle Sam or Lincoln?) hanging from trapeze rings bearing labels of "utter ruin," "emancipation," "paper money," "brag buncomb". [Current Problems], 1862 (Folder FF-81, Item 1862-15)
    Pen drawing: Signed A.J. Lynde, Nov. 16th, 1862. Acquisition(?) date on front: May 15, 1906.
  - [No Title] Drawing shows three figures - Uncle Sam represented as Death looks on as two soldiers examine their dismembered bodies. [Social], 1862 (Folder FF-81, Item 1862-16)
    Pen drawing: Signed A.J. Lynde, delt., 1862. Acquisition(?) date on front: May 15, 1906.
  - [Four pen drawings, unsigned, titled "The Little Napoleon's Virginia Campaign, 1861-2." [General McClellan], 1862 (Folder FF-81, Item 1862-17)
  - Southern "Volunteers". [Confederate Coercion re Recruits], 1862 (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-18)
    Lithograph: No imprint. Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting". Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946.
  - Re-Union on the Secesh-Democratic Plan. [Secession, Slavery, Confederate Debt], 1862 (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-19)
  - The Bill-Posters Dream. Cross Readings to be Read Downwards. [Social satire of advertising], 1862 (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-20)
    Lithograph: B. Derby, del. Two copies.
  - The Blockade on the "Connecticut Plan." Respectfully dedicated to the Secretary of the Navy. [Inefficiency of Gideon Welles; Relative strength of Confederate Navy to Union Navy], 1862 (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-21)
    Lithograph: Published by Currier & Ives. Acquisition(?) date on front: Sept. 27, 1901.
  - [No Title] Drawing shows Lincoln standing on Constitution with an African-American woman, holding latter's infant. Two male abolitionists in background. "Tribune" tax bill and a tombstone "in memory of American liberty" in foreground. [Lincoln's choice of anti-slavery over the Union], 1862 (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-22)
    Oil on canvas: unsigned. Acquisition(?) date on back: Feb. 3, 1904.
  - The Last Round. Won by Little Mac against Big Charley. [Charles Lee, George McClellan], 1862 (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-23)
    Lithograph: Signed Potomac. Acquisition(?) date on front: Apr. 12, 1906.
  - Breaking that "Backbone". [Union approaches to breaking the Confederacy; Emancipation Proclamation], 1862 (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-24)
    Lithograph: Signed B. Day del. Published by Currier & Ives.
  - The Man of Words [Under picture of Horatio Seymour exhorting mob at burning of Colored Orphan Asylum]. The Man of Deeds. [Under Picture of Confederate generals surrendering to Grant] Which Do You Think The Country Needs?, 1862 (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-25)
    Lithograph: Designed drawn by Cameron. Published by Currier & Ives. Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting". Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946.
  - A Disloyal British "Subject". [British neutrality], 1862 (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-26)
    Acquisition(?) date on front: May 15, 1906. Lithograph published by Currier & Ives.
  - [Two drawings mounted together] "Where is Jackson?" pen drawing, unsigned; "One could listen to all the other could talk." pencil, signed Ruggles., 1862 (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-27)
    Written note on front referring to bottom drawing: Gen. Rosencranz and Gen. Fremont. Upper drawing is of Stonewall Jackson and his ability to elude the Union Army.
  - [Three drawings] "The President gives another pointed hint" [Lincoln urging McClellan to Richmond], pen drawing; "Lyman Beecher", pencil drawing; No title [George McClellan], pencil drawing., 1862 (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-28)
    Third drawing has no title but verse below is as follows: "The war is a failure proclaimed little Mack, T'was true while he was in command But he ought to have taken some of it back When Ulysses Grant took a hand."
  - Good bye Massa, nebber see you ginn. [Secession as end of slavery], 1862 (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-29)
    Pencil drawing: Anonymous.
  - [Four prints on one sheet] "Tall oaks from little acorns grow"; "The Romans placed hay upon the horns of vicious oxen"; "A snow scene in Richmond"; "Tall oaks from little acorns grow"., 1862 (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-30)
    Etching. On each under title: "Pages from the unpublished history of a celebrated financier"
  - The Voluntary Manner in Which Some of the Southern Volunteers Enlist. [Confederate Coercion of Recruits], 1862 (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-31)
    Lithograph:Thos. Worth del., no imprint (Currier & Ives?). Acquisition(?) date on front: July 8, 1903.
  - A Startling Announcement., 1862 (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-32)
    Lithograph: Published by Currier & Ives. Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting". Acquisition(?) date on back: October 7, 1946. Written note on front: "Ft. Donelson fell in 1862"
  - Grand Sweepstakes for 1862. Won by Celebrated Horse "Emancipation" (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-33)
    Lithograph: Signed Potomac. No imprint. Acquisition(?) date on back: Dec. 6, 1950.
  - The Emblem of the Free. With original music. The Traitor's Dream, by Samuel Canty. No. 3 [Jefferson Davis crowned by Satan, haunted by George Washington], 1862 (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-34)
    Lithograph: B. Day, del. Respectfully inscribed to Thomas H. Faron and William Atkinson, Esqr's. No. 3. Includes two lines of music composed by John J. Daly and five verses. Acquisition(?) date on front: July 17, 1905.
  - The Traitor's Soliloquy. The Traitor's Dream, by Samuel Canty. No 1 [Jefferson Davis], 1862 (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-35)
    Lithograph: Signed B. Day. Entered ... 1862 by Samuel Canty ... Respectfully inscribed to Thomas H. Faron and William Atkinson Esq'rs. Acquisition(?) date on front: July 17, 1905.
  - "Our Special." [Satire of artists supposedly drawing battle scenes from life], 1862 (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-36)
    Lithograph: col., by Frank Skinner copyrighted in Connecticut, 1862. Stamped on back: Bella C. Landauer Collection.
  - The Traitor and His Daughter. The Traitor's Dream by Samuel Canty. No. 2. [Jefferson Davis choosing ambition over family], 1862 (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-37)
    Lithograph: Signed B. Day, del. Entered ... 1862 by Samuel Canty... Respectfully inscribed to Thomas H. Faron and William Atkinson Esq'rs. Glued on front appears to be a signature of Samuel Canty.
  - Brother Jonathan Calls on the Lancashire Weaver., 1862 (Folder FF-82, Item 1862-38)
    Written date on front: Dec. 27, 1862.
  - [Lincoln Writing the Emancipation Proclamation], 1863 (Folder FF-83, Item 1863-1)
    Etching: Unsigned. By Blada (pseudonym of Adalbert J. Volck). See [Collection of] Sketches from the Civil War in North America. London, 1863, by same author. 2 copies.
  - [Lincoln and Benjamin F. Butler as Don Quixote and Sancho Panza], 1863 (Folder FF-83, Item 1863-2)
    Etching: by Adalbert J. Volck, Confederate Government Agent, reproduced in "Sketches of the Civil War in North America" 1863.
  - King of the Cannibal Islands - Abe Lincoln's Court - Suppressed - (in pencil), 1863 (Folder FF-83, Item 1863-3)
    Etching: by A.J. Volck, Confederate Agent (?). Acquisition(?) date on front: Apr. 16, 1906.
  - Confederate War etchings, 1862 (Box PR-10.1, Item 1863-4)
    29 etchings on copper by A.J. Volck. These are inventoried in a separate finding aid: Guide to the Confederate War Etchings
  - The Modern Andromeda. [Woman chained by "War Policy", threatened by monster], 1863 (Folder FF-83, Item 1863-5)
    Pen Drawing: signed by A.J.Lynde. 1863. Acquisition(?) date on front: May 15, 1906
  - Offering a Substitute. A Scene in the Office of the Provost Marshall. [Union draft substitutes], 1863 (Folder FF-83, Item 1863-6)
    Lithograph: Published by J.L. Magee, Philadelphia. Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting". Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946.
  - The House that Jeff Built. [Twelve pictures and verses about slavery], 1863 (Folder FF-83, Item 1863-7)
    Etching: Entered...1863 by D.C. Johnston...Massachusetts. Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting". Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946.
  - A Pair of "Noble Brothers" [Benjamin Wood of the Daily News & Horace Greeley of the Tribune], 1863 (Folder FF-83, Item 1863-8)
    Lithograph: No imprint. Acquisition(?) date on front: Apr. 12, 1906.
  - The Meeting of the Friends, City Hall Park. [Horatio Seymour, Draft Riots], 1863 (Folder FF-83, Item 1863-9)
    Wood engraving: By H.L. Stephens-Weitenkampf (?). Below engraving is 8 lines of dialogue between Horatio Seymour, Gov. of New York, and rioters. 2 copies.
  - The Pending Conflict. [States' rights, secession, European satisfaction over Civil War], 1863 (Folder FF-83, Item 1863-10)
    Lithograph: Designed by O.E. Woods, published by Herline & Hensel, Lith. Entered...1863 by Oliver Evans Woods...Pennsylvania. Below lithograph, dialogue among Emp. Napoleon, John Bull, Secesh, and U.S. Citizen Soldier. Similar to item 1863-20. Acquisition(?) date on front: Apr. 12, 1906.
  - "I say Billy, do you know why I'm doing this? Cause, I'm going to run for Congress soon!" [Abolitionist sentiments for political advantage], 1863 (Folder FF-83, Item 1863-11)
    Lithograph: Signed Potomac. No imprint. Acquisition(?) date on front: Apr. 12, 1906.
  - The Ghost. [European concern over war over slavery and liberty], 1863 (Folder FF-83, Item 1863-12)
    Lithograph: Published by Currier & Ives. Acquisition(?) date on front: July 8, 1903.
  - Home. "On Sick Leave", 1863 (Folder FF-83, Item 1863-13)
    Lithograph: Signed Edw.J. Mullen, published by Currier & Ives. Missing as of November 30, 2021.
  - City Inspector Boole At Work. [Slaughterhouse Reform], 1863 (Folder FF-83, Item 1863-14)
    Lithograph: Lith. of Henry C. Eno.
  - No Title. [Reproduction of Thomas Nast drawing depicting Confederate General Wade Hampton with three Yankee soldiers suspended from scaffold in the background], 1863 (Folder FF-83, Item 1863-15)
    Reproduction of drawing by Thomas Nast.
  - No Title. [Reproduction of Thomas Nast drawing showing lynching/burning in New York during Draft Riots], 1863 (Folder FF-83, Item 1863-16)
  - The (Fort) Monroe Doctrine. [Runaway "contraband"], 1863 (Folder FF-83, Item 1863-17)
    Lithograph: No imprint. Acquisition(?) date on front: May 15, 1906.
  - Two etchings: "Great American Tragedians, Comedians, Clowns, and Rope Danzers [sic] in their favorite characters." (Lincoln as Court Jester); "Mokanna" (Lincoln as Arabian dancing girl)., 1863 (Folder FF-83, Item 1863-18)
    Etching: unsigned, by A.J. Volck, Confederate agent.
  - John Bull in a Quandary. [British debt and European position on Civil War sides], 1863 (Folder FF-83, Item 1863-19)
    Lithograph: Signed Fritz. No imprint. Acquisition(?) date on front: Apr. 6, 1906.
  - The Pending Contest. [States' rights, secession, European satisfaction over Civil War], 1863 (Folder FF-83, Item 1863-20)
    Similar to item 1863-10. Lithograph: By O.E. Woods, published by Herline & Hensel, Lith.
  - "Black Jack and Sooty Jim". Portraits of the Republican Candidates as painted by the Democrats. [Porter Case], 1863 (Folder FF-83, Item 1863-21)
    Pencil drawing: unsigned.
  - Pictorial Nick-Nax, For the Holidays 1863-1864. (Folder FF-84, Item No #)
    8 page large folio supplement to the humor magazine, Nick-Nax.
  - Political Caricature no. 2. Miscegenation, or the Millennium of Abolitionism., 1864 (Folder FF-85, Item 1864-1)
    Lithograph: Entered...1864 by Bromley & Co. 2 copies, one hand colored
  - Political Caricature no. 3. The Abolition Catastrophe, or the November Smash-up., 1864 (Folder FF-85, Item 1864-2)
    Lithograph: Entered...1864 by Bromley & Co. 2 copies, one hand colored.
  - Political Caricature no. 4. The Miscegenation Ball., 1864 (Folder FF-85, Item 1864-3)
    Signed Thomas; Lith: Kimmel & Forster, Entered...1864 by Bromley & Co. 2 copies, one hand colored.
  - Our Foreign Relations. [Liberty as U.S. strength against European colonial powers], 1864 (Folder FF-85, Item 1864-4)
    Lithograph: Drawn by Hochstein, Lith. by A. Brett, Entered...1864 by N.P. Beers... Acquisition(?) date on front: Apr. 16, 1906.
  - Political Caricature no. 1. The Grave of the Union. Or Major Jack Downing's Dream, Drawn by Zeke. [War as threat to democracy and constitution], 1864 (Folder FF-85, Item 1864-5)
  - No Title. Two pen drawings: "Congress should drive Lincoln out of the White House; Compromise with the South slavery"; "God Save the Union!" [Elite support for compromise vs. military and working class sacrifice for Union], 1864 (Folder FF-85, Item 1864-6)
    Two Pen Drawings: Signed P.Kramer. First, Anti-Lincoln because of his anti-slavery views. Second, Depicting McClellan carried off battlefield. Acquisition(?) date on front: Dec. 6, 1906.
  - Northern Coat of Arms. [Liberty cap/rhetoric hiding underlying cause of abolition], 1864 (Folder FF-85, Item 1864-7)
    Lithograph: By J.E. Baker-Weitenkampf (?), Entered...1864 by J.E. Cutler. Acquisition(?) date on front: Jan. 8, 1907.
  - Slow and Steady Wins the Race. [Lincoln & McClellan], 1864 (Folder FF-85, Item 1864-8)
    Lithograph: No imprint. Acquisition(?) date on front: Sept. 27, 1907.
  - "I knew him, Horatio; a Fellow of Infinite Jest. *** Where be your Gibes Now?" - Hamlet, Act IV, Sc. 1. [Lincoln & McClellan], 1864 (Folder FF-85, Item 1864-9)
    Wood Engraving: Signed Howard, del.
  - Little Mac's Double Feat of Equitation. [McClellan], 1864 (Folder FF-85, Item 1864-10)
    Lithograph: Entered...1864...N. Bangs Williams, Providence.
  - A Thrilling Incident during Voting,-- 18th Ward, Philadelphia, Oct. 11. [Former Democrat voting Republican], 1864 (Folder FF-85, Item 1864-11)
    Lithograph: Signed Harley, del., no imprint. Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting". Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946.
  - Your Plan and Mine. [McClellan & Lincoln], 1864 (Folder FF-85, Item 1864-12)
  - The Political "Siamese" Twins, The Offspring of Chicago Miscegenation. {McClellan & Pendleton], 1864 (Folder FF-85, Item 1864-13)
    Lithograph: Published by Currier & Ives. 1864-13 (Copy 1): Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting". Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946. A second copy of 1864-13 is physically attached to 1864-51; see that item.
  - Little Mac, In his Great Two Horse Act, in the Presidential Canvass of 1864. (Folder FF-85, Item 1864-14)
    Wood Engraving: Signed Howard, del., published by T.W. Strong. Acquisition(?) date on front: Sept. 27, 1901.
  - The Chicago Platform, What is it, Peace or War., 1864 (Folder FF-85, Item 1864-15)
    Lithograph: By H.L. Stephens-Weitenkampf (?), no imprint. Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting". Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946.
  - The Chicago Platform., 1864 (Folder FF-85, Item 1864-16)
  - Heads of the Democracy., 1864 (Folder FF-85, Item 1864-17)
    Lithograph: No imprint. 1864-17 (Copy 1): Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting". Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946. A second copy is physically attached to 1864-50; see that item.
  - Democracy: 1832, 1864. [John Calhoun & Andrew Jackson; Jefferson Davis & George McClellan] (Folder FF-85, Item 1864-18)
    Lithograph: Published by L. Prang & Co. Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting".
  - How Free Ballot is Protected! [Armed African-American preventing votes for McClellan/Democratic Party], 1864 (Folder FF-85, Item 1864-19)
    Lithograph: Signed J.E. Baker, del., No imprint. Acquisition(?) date on front: Nov. 13, 1899.
  - Little Mac Trying to Dig his Way to the White House but is Frightened by Spiritual Manifestations.-, 1864 (Folder FF-85, Item 1864-20)
    Lithograph: N.p.n.d. Two copies. 1864-20 (Copy 2): Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting". Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946.
  - The Gunboat Candidate at the Battle of Malvern Hill. [George McClellan], 1864 (Folder FF-86, Item 1864-21)
    Lithograph: Published by Currier & Ives. 1864-21 (Copy 1): Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting". Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946. Second copy: Stamped on back, "Collection of The New-York Historical Society"; in pencil on front, "Dup."
  - The Chicago Platform and Candidate. [George McClellan], 1864 (Folder FF-86, Item 1864-22)
    Lithograph: Pulblished by Currier & Ives. Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting". Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946.
  - The Popular Prejudice and Judicial Blindness of the People of the U.S. Constitution, - Or The Constitution as People have been Accustomed to See it. [Lincoln & Slavery], 1864 (Folder FF-86, Item 1864-23)
    Wood Engraving: Anonymous. Acquisition(?) date on front: Apr. 6, 1908.
  - The Sportsman upset by the Recoil of his own Gun. (Jo. Miller) [Lincoln], 1864 (Folder FF-86, Item 1864-24)
    Reproduction of pen drawing: Monogram CLA. Acquisition(?) date on front: Sept. 23, 1901.
  - Running the "Machine". [Lincoln & Cabinet], 1864 (Folder FF-86, Item 1864-25)
    Lithograph: Published by Currier & Ives. 2 copies. The second copy is stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting". Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946. Also stamped on back: "Collections of The New-York Historical Society" and date in pencil - 5/9/1908.
  - Abe Linking with his Significantly Named Cabinet. [8 lines of description follow.] [Lincoln & Cabinet], 1864 (Folder FF-86, Item 1864-26)
    Lithograph: Designed by R.D. Goodwin; "Entered...1864 by M.E. Goodwin..."; Acquisition(?) date on front: May 15, 1906.
  - Abraham's Dream! - "Coming events cast their shadows before". [McClellan winning election], 1864 (Folder FF-86, Item 1864-27)
  - The Commander-in-Chief conciliating the Soldier's Votes on the Battle Field. [Lincoln & McClellan], 1864 (Folder FF-86, Item 1864-28)
    Reproduction of pen drawing: Monogram CLA. Acquisition(?) date on front: Apr. 16, 1906.
  - Leading, Following, Rebelling. [Fremont, Lincoln & McClellan], 1864 (Folder FF-86, Item 1864-29)
  - Columbia Demands her Children! [Lincoln, Opposition to Draft], 1864 (Folder FF-86, Item 1864-30)
    Lithograph: Signed J.E. Baker, del. No imprint. Acquisition(?) date on front: Sept. 27, 1907.
  - Union and Liberty! and Union and Slavery! [Lincoln & McClellan], 1864 (Folder FF-86, Item 1864-31)
    Wood Engraving: Published by M.W. Siebert, printer. Acquisition(?) date on front: June 12, 190_ (?).
  - How Columbia receives McClellan's Salutation from the Chicago platform., 1864 (Folder FF-86, Item 1864-32)
    Wood Engraving: Reproduction.
  - Platforms Illustrated. [Lincoln & McClellan], 1864 (Folder FF-87, Item 1864-33)
    Lithograph: No imprint. Acquisition(?) date on front: Apr. 2, 1906.
  - Caving In, Or A Rebel "Deeply Humiliated". [Lincoln winning the war], 1864 (Folder FF-87, Item 1864-34)
    Lithograph: Signed Ben Day, del.; Published by Currier & Ives.
  - The True Issue Or "Thats Whats the Matter". [Lincoln and McClellan], 1864 (Folder FF-87, Item 1864-35)
  - Head Quarters at Harrison's Landing. "See Evidence before Committee on Conduct of the War." [McClellan ineffectiveness as general], 1864 (Folder FF-87, Item 1864-36)
    Lithograph: No imprint.
  - Desperate Peace Man. [McClellan & Pendleton surrendering liberty to Jefferson Davis], 1864 (Folder FF-87, Item 1864-37)
  - The Hand-Writing on the Wall, Or the Modern Belshazzar. [Impending defeat of he Confederacy, Jefferson Davis], 1864 (Folder FF-87, Item 1864-38)
  - Copperheads Worshipping Their Idol. [McClellan], 1864 (Folder FF-87, Item 1864-39)
  - A Little Game of Bagatelle, Between Old Abe The Rail Splitter & Little Mac The Gunboat General., 1864 (Folder FF-87, Item 1864-40)